# Mostafa S. Ibrahim

## Personal Data

British Columbia, Canada **ADDRESS** 

+1 604 401 0810 **PHONE** 

**EMAIL** mostafa.saad.fci@gmail.com (Primary) | msibrahi@sfu.ca Website | Linkedin | Github | Google Scholar | Ask | YouTube Links

# **INTERESTS**

I have a mix of experience in Software Engineering, 2D Computer Vision Research and Algorithms Design. My interests are to apply Computer vision & Machine Learning to solve real-world problems in roles that preferably involve leadership (so far have two short industrial leadership roles and volunteer supervision activity).

## SKILLS

**COMPUTER VISION R&D** 8 years in Deep Learning, Action Recognition, Human Group Activities, Classification, Object Detection, Semantic Segmentation, Human/Hand Pose Estimation, Gaze Estimation, Object Tracking, GANs, Domain Adaptation 5 years in Payment(Java EE), Storage Management (C++) SOFTWARE ENGINEERING 5 years (competitions): ICPC World Finalist, Trainer, Chief Judge, Coach ALGORITHMIC SKILLS PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Python, C++, Java, Matlab TensorFlow, Caffe, Lasnge, OpenCV, LibSVM, Java EE frameworks

# **EDUCATION**

**FRAMEWORKS** 

2015-2018 Ph.D. in Computer Science, Simon Fraser University, Canada

SUPERVISOR Prof Greg Mori - Computer Vision Field

Worked in Multi-person Activity Understanding - GPA: 3.92/4

Publications in CVPR, ECCV, and others

2 Internships: Vision Engineering (Google) & Vision Research (D-wave)

Keywords: Deep learning, C++, Caffe, Python, Lasagne, Tensorflow, Temporal Models

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Cairo University, Egypt 2010-2012

SUPERVISOR: Prof Amr Badr, Computer Vision Field Worked in Image Object Detection: Object Proposals Approach

2004-2008 Hon. B.Sc. in Computer Science, Cairo University, Egypt

GPA: 3.83/4 (3rd on class)

Graduation Project: Programming Online Judge, Using Java, JSF Framework Internship: IBM Egypt, Summer 2007 in Employees Evaluation System

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Mar 2019-Present

#### Computer Vision Researcher at HUAWEI, Canada

Working on interesting computer vision and machine learning R&D challenges. Mentoring interns.

Keywords: Tensorflow, PyTorch, Hand Pose Estimation, Domain Adaptation, Traffic Control Gesture Recognition

#### Nov 2018-Mar 2019

## Computer Vision Researcher | Team Lead at FLEX A.I., Canada

Fitness application: built in a short time a challenging computer vision feature

My Team: Me (lead) and a Machine Learning Engineer

Proposed a problem reformulation, practical annotations process and processing pipeline

Implemented the pipeline and made ready for back-end integration.

Keywords: Python, Tensorflow, Human Pose Estimation, Video Classification, AWS

#### Mar 2018-Oct 2018

## Computer Vision Research Intern at D-WAVE, Canada

Worked in Semi-supervised Semantic Segmentation Project - Paper accepted @CVPR Keywords: Python, Tensorflow, Semantic Segmentation, PASCAL VOC

SUPERVISOR Arash Vahdat

## May 2016-Aug 2016

## Java Software Engineer Intern at Google, USA

Worked in the photos team: investigating a feature for the photos app

Designed, developed and tested the feature internally

My Evaluation was very positive: very productive and needed minimal supervision

Google offered another internship without interviewing process

TEAM LEAD Jingyu Cui

#### Aug 2014-Apr 2016

### C++ Senior Computer Vision Engineer at HERUOLABS, Germany

Worked remotely from Egypt: full time for 5 months, then 40% part time during PhD

Developed vision modules in detection, object proposals and tracking

Developed tools to facilitate complex models training

Developed a gateway to receive vision queries and process them

Lead small research to work on some unsupervised learning problems

Keywords: C++, Opency, Caffe, CGI, Appache, AWS

## Jul 2011-Jul 2014

# C++ Software Engineer at NTP, USA

Worked remotely from Egypt in a data storage management software named NTP QFS

Team was maintaining Disk Quota Policies to limit user consumption

Customizing the policies to meet the specific needs of your individual users Managing file data use across: the enterprise, multiple platforms, storage types

# Jun 2010-Mar 2011

## Research Assistant at MICROSOFT, Egypt

Computer Vision Field - Semantic Image Segmentation problem

Contribution: Potential values in a discrete energy minimization setup

Supervisor: Prof Dr Motaz El Saban. Programming Languages: C++, Matlab

#### Nov 2008-May 2010

#### Java Software Engineer at FAWRY, Egypt

Team was building a bill presentment and payment network to handle the bills through the various electronic channels available at **banks**; including ATMs, the internet, mobile phones and point of sales.

Technology: Java EE(JSF web, JPA, Web services, JMS)

## RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS

- Mostafa S. Ibrahim, Arash Vahdat, Mani Ranjbar, William G. Macready. Semi-Supervised Semantic Image Segmentation with Self-correcting Networks, in CVPR 2020
- Mostafa S. Ibrahim, Greg Mori. Hierarchical Relational Networks for Group Activity Recognition and Retrieval, in ECCV 2018. Github
- Jiawei He, Zhiwei Deng, Mostafa S. Ibrahim, Greg Mori. Generic Tubelet Proposals for Action Localization, in WACV 2018
- Mehran Khodabandeh, Zhiwei Deng, **Mostafa S. Ibrahim**, Shinichi Satoh, Greg Mori. Active Learning for Structured Prediction from Partially Labeled Data, in arXiv, 2017
- Mostafa S. Ibrahim, Srikanth Muralidharan, Zhiwei Deng, Arash Vahdat, Greg Mori.
  A Hierarchical Deep Temporal Model for Group Activity Recognition, in CVPR 2016.
  Github
- Mostafa S. Ibrahim, Amr A. Badr, Mostafa R. Abdallah and Ibrahim F. Eissa. Bounding Box Object Localization Based On Image Superpixelization, in Procedia CS 2012
- Mostafa S. Ibrahim and Motaz A. El Saban. Higher order potentials with superpixel neighbourhood (hsn) for semantic image segmentation, in ICIP 2011

## PROGRAMMING CONTESTS ACTIVITY

- Part of SFU ACM ICPC Administration team/WPC in 2017 & 2018.
- Active International Coach with 30+ trainees yearly from several nationalities.
- Judge & Problem Setter in Arabian Regional ACM ICPC 2013.
- Chief Judge in Egyptian & Jordanian National ACM ICPC in 2012.
- 2011 ACM ICPC World Finalist in Orlando, Florida USA.
- 2nd rank 2009 and 2nd rank 2010 in Arab Collegiate Programming Contest.
- 2nd rank 2006, 5th rank 2008 and 1st rank 2009 in Egyptian National ACM ICPC.
- 8th rank in 2005 Egypt Olympiad in Informatics (EOI), Silver Medal.
- Have a YouTube Channel (250+ videos 33k subscribers).
- Designed a popular Training sheet for new trainees.

#### **OTHERS**

- Teaching Assistant (2008-2014), Cairo University. Courses: Programming, Software Engineering, Data Structures and Algorithms, Neural Network, Genetic Programming.
- Author for 2 programming courses @Udemy (Mastering Critical skills series)
- Conducted Computer Vision Study Group in Cairo University in 2012-2013 & in SFU 2016.
- Organized Arabic Computer Vision Webinar Series.
- Co-organized Machine Learning Day in Cairo University in 2011.
- Active volunteer on Ask.fm for Helping students (Answered 63K questions).
- Much fun: Gym, Football, Organizing BBQs & social gathering.